站那儿别动
Stop right there.
把手放在我能看到的地方
Put your hands where I can see them.
脱衬衫
Shirt off!
快点
Come on!
裤子也脱了 快 狗娘养的
Pants off! Come on, motherfucker.
我一直以为我会在
I always thought my life would end like this,
某个鸟不生蛋的地方
in some Godforsaken place,
被一颗莫名而来的子弹了却残生
from a bullet I didn't see coming.
我只是从没想过我会在乎
I just never thought I'd care.
《快枪查理》
"查理.斯威夫特 美国海军陆战队光荣退役"
你应该不会愿意看到
One thing you don't want to see,
大早上穿着正装的我
me in a suit this early in the morning.
这代表着我正在工作
Means I'm working,
同时也意味着将会有人
which means someone is about
死于非命
to depart this life unexpectedly.
"密西西比州 比洛克希市"
-斯坦  -是我
-Stan.  -Yeah?
-他迟到了  -没事的
-He's late.  -It's all right.
他会来的 OK?
He'll be there, okay?
嘿 听着 我自己能搞定这家伙
Hey, listen, I can do the guy myself.
-他现在就在那儿  -不不不
-He's there right now.  -No, no, no, no.
另外 我答应过鲍比.T 要给这孩子一个机会
Besides, I promised Bobby T we'd give this kid a shot.
他刀法不错
Supposed to be pretty good with a knife.
是 你总这么说 但…
Yeah, well that's what you keep saying, but..
好了 完事了给我打电话 OK?
Well, uh, call me when it's done, okay?
-他来了  -嘿 我给罗路买了这个
-He's here.  -Hey, I got these for Rollo.
我听说他超爱吃甜甜圈
'Cause I.. I heard he's a donut junkie.
所以 我跟他说
So, I told him that he won
他在我们的每周抽奖中赢了一打甜甜圈
a dozen donuts at our weekly raffle.
他喜欢波士顿奶油
He loves Boston creams.
嗯… 为啥穿得这么正式?
W.. What's with the suit?
-你这T恤又是咋回事?  - 哦 这是计划的一部分
-What's with the shirt?  -Oh, it's part of the plan.
我自己做的(脆皮奶脆)
I made it myself.
-聪明吧?  -行
-That's pretty smart, right?  -Yeah.
不过那家店叫“酥皮奶酥"
Except Krispy Kremes are spelled with two K's.
谁他妈知道
Who the fuck knows that?
反正你不知道
Not you.
OK 动作快点 就一次机会
Okay, make it quick. You get one chance.
你搞砸的话 找他又得一顿好找
You fuck it up, he's in the wind again.
嘿
Hey.
别担心 老家伙
Don't worry, old timer.
我能搞定
I got this shit.
"根据维克托.吉士勒小说《枪猴》改编"
特雷弗
Trevor!
咋了?
Yeah?
这是什么?
What is this?
好 伙计 好的 谢谢
All right, man. All right. Thanks.
再见
See ya!
-那就是罗路  -对
-That was Rollo.  -Yeah.
为什么不用刀?
Why didn't you stab him?
我一直都用刀
That's what I always do.
-所以他们叫你刀仔  -没错
-Hence why they call you Blade.  -Yeah.
-我想换个花样  -嗯哼?
-I thought I'd do something different.  -Mm  -hmm?
我想向斯坦展示我的其它技能和想象力
I wanna show Stan some range and imagination.
你做了什么? 给他下毒?
What'd you do, poison him?
什么鬼?
What the fuck?
波士顿奶油 宝贝
Boston cream, baby!
哇哦
Woo!
来
Come on.
你在甜甜圈里放了什么?
What did you put in the donut?
呃 那个 就像 一个小炸弹
Uh, just, like, a little blasting cap.
哦
Oh.
我是说 没有头
I mean, how's Beggar
拜加会认得没有脑袋的罗路吗?
gonna know it's Rollo without his head?
-呃 那可能就…  -你他妈给我闭嘴
-Well, there's like a..  -Shut the fuck up.
天哪
Sweet Jesus.
-班尼  -怎么样了?
-Benny.  -How'd it go?
那小伙儿给罗路喂了一个装有炸弹的甜甜圈
Kid fed Rollo a donut with a bomb in it.
-听起来挺酷的  -嗯哼
-That sounds kinda cool.  -Uh  -huh.
爆了他的头
Blew his head off.
我是说 呃 斯坦听到会尿裤子的
I mean.. Uh, Stan gonna shit himself.
嘿 听着 没必要打扰斯坦
Hey, listen, there's no need to bother Stan.
我来处理
I'll take care of it.
你认识一个认识罗路的人 对吧?
You know a guy that knew Rollo, right?
查查他在这附近有没有家人 好吗?
Find out if he had any family around here, will ya?
好的
All right.
克莱默小姐?
Miss Kramer?
-很抱歉打扰你  -罗路死了?
-I'm sorry to disturb you.  -Rollo's dead.
-是的  -被人杀了?
-Yes.  -Whacked?
是的 没错
As it were, yes.
是的
As it were.
好吧 谢谢你的提醒
Well, thanks for the heads up.
我会去查查他到底有没有买
I'll make sure to look up that life insurance policy
人寿保险
he never got around to getting.
我来是想问个问题
I came here to discuss a problem that's arisen.
如果我对你的问题不感兴趣呢?
And if I'm not interested in your problem?
哦 那么…
Oh, well...
我明白了
I see.
你会用胶带封住我的嘴
You'll slap duct tape over my mouth
然后把我塞进后备箱
and shove me in the trunk.
除非你对这个感兴趣
Only if you're into that kind of thing.
只是想聊会
Just wanna talk.
车里等我 甜甜圈
Wait in the car, Donut.
你刚刚杀了我的前夫 就不请你喝了
I'd offer you one, but you just killed my ex.
可你看起来并不伤心
You don't seem too upset.
就凭他做的那些勾当
I expected him to be deceased long before today,
我还以为他早就挂了
given the business he was in.
咦?
Huh.
你喜欢收集动物尸体 克莱默小姐?
You have a thing for dead animals, Miss Kramer?
我叫玛茜 是个标本师
Marcie. I'm a taxidermist.
嗯 这样的人不多
Mm. Don't find many of those.
很小众
It's a niche thing.
他看起来很生气
He looks angry.
就像有人偷了他的橡子 他要让他们付出代价
Like someone stole his acorns and he's gonna make 'em pay.
真的吗?
Really?
我不太懂海狸的表达方式
I'm not up on my beaver expressions.
-我可能说错了  -我想表达它愤怒的情绪
-I could be wrong.  -I was going for indignant.
哦 是的 我明白了
Oh, yeah. I see it.
千万别乱动我的橡子
Don't ever mess with my acorns.
我这里有个小问题 呃…
I have a small problem, Miss, uh..
-玛茜  -玛茜
-Marcie.  -Marcie.
我必须向某人证明
I have to convince a certain person
外面后备箱里的尸体确实是罗路
that the body in that trunk out there is indeed Rollo.
脸花了?
Something happen to his face?
对 脸没了
Yeah. It's missing.
连同他头部的其他部分
Along with the rest of his head.
如果你能陪我走一趟
There's five grand in it for you
证明罗路确实是罗路 就能拿五千块
if you come with me and vouch that Rollo is indeed Rollo.
我需要钱
I could use the money.
但我发过誓不会再沾你们的圈子
But I swore I'd never get back into that world.
所以 我给你省点钱 也给自己省点时间
So, I'll save you the dough and myself some time.
我哥哥是个纹身师
Brother's a tattoo artist.
他给我和罗路纹了一对情侣纹身当作结婚礼物
Gave Rollo and I matching tattoos as a wedding gift.
-哦  -在我们的屁股上
-Oh.  -Our ass cheeks.
我去年把纹身洗了
I had Rollo removed last year.
你为什么要这么做?
Why'd you?
消除他的痕迹?
Have him removed?
我不知道
I don't know.
正常人都会吧
It's usually along the lines of someone
不然咋和其他人约会啊上床啊什么的
trying to fuck someone else over, that type of thing.
对这档子事儿罗路可是乐此不疲
That type of thing would be on the top of Rollo's resume.
是啊 明白了吧
Well, there you go now.
总之 他回到了比洛克希
Anyway, he.. He made it back here to Biloxi
而这恰好是我老板的地盘
and it just happens to be my boss's territory.
所以 我们对新奥尔良的同事们很客气
So, we're being courteous to our colleagues in New Orleans.
我喜欢你们的彬彬有礼
I love how you guys are so courteous.
打开后备箱 甜甜圈
Pop the trunk, Donut.
这窗帘真吓人
Horrible drapes.
是啊 很衬那间厨房
Yeah, they went nice with the kitchen.
-这就是罗路的屁股  -看到没? 来吧 伙计
-That's Rollo's ass.  -See? Come on, man.
我们不需要他的人头了
We didn't need his head, after all.
你白生气了
You got all pissy for nothing.
-你为什么不…  -啊哦
-Why don't you...  -Oops.
你肯定不知道 拜加和罗路在安哥拉做过好监友
Bet you didn't know Beggars and Rollo were cellmates at Angola.
他肯定近距离看过那个纹身
Pretty sure he's seen that tattoo up close.
斯坦会不高兴的 甜甜圈
Stan's not gonna like this, Donut.
-别叫我甜甜圈  -好吧
-Stop calling me Donut!  -Okay.
枪拿出来 枪
Get your gun out! Gun!
现在
Now.
扔车里
Put it in the car.
去他的斯坦
Fuck Stan.
拜加说我可以随时来为他工作
Beggar said I could come work for him anytime.
他势头正旺
He's moving up.
这个正好能当我的投名状
And this'll prove I'm ready for his crew.
要是再听到有人叫我甜甜圈
If I ever hear anybody call me Donut again,
我就回来活剐了你
I'm gonna come back and I'm gonna gut you.
老东西
Old timer.
别叫我甜甜圈 操你妈的
Don't call me Donut, motherfucker!
我想我还不知道你的名字
I don't believe I got your name.
查理
Charlie.
我要发达了 我要发达了
I'm moving up, baby! I'm moving up!
呜！
Woo!
哦 嘘
Ooh, sh..
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
你以前和他合作过吗?
Have you worked with him before?
不 是第一次
No, first time.
-真是一团糟  -没事 车是偷的
-What a mess.  -It's okay. The car is stolen.
我是说那小子 看起来射到了自己
I was referring to the kid. Looks like he shot himself.
嗯 他更擅长用刀
Well, he was more of a knife guy.
见鬼
Shit.
嗯…
Well...
你知道 他俩…
you know, they're kinda..
个头差不多
Kinda the same size.
也许可以去找找你哥哥
Maybe go visit your brother,
他是纹身师 也许他可以… 你懂的
the tattoo artist, maybe he could, you know,
再纹一个 咋样?
kinda.. No?
好吧 但我不会砍下他的头
Fine, but I'm not cutting his head off.
玛卡.罗尔著《前世绘》
"是的 斯科蒂.波特
Yeah, Scotty Porter
"在场上很活跃
looking a lot more active out there.
他进步得真快 这家伙"
He's really coming along, that guy.
-你放了香菜?  -没
-You put cilantro in here?  -No.
嗯 我明显尝到了柠檬的味道
Well, I distinctly taste lemon.
-对 这叫柠檬  -我讨厌香菜
-Yeah. It's called lemon.  -I detest cilantro.
所以我用的柠檬
That's why I used lemon.
你 这鸡肉是在多米尼克餐厅买的吗?
Did you.. Did you get this chicken at that Domenic's?
多米尼克餐厅在北末广场 比洛克希可没有
Domenic's is in the North End. We're in Biloxi.
对啊 我脑子短路了估计
That's right, I don't know what the heck's gotten into me.
总之 重点是 它很好吃 别误会我的意思
Anyway, the point is, it's very good, don't get me wrong.
即便是加香菜 也很好吃
It's very good, even with the cilantro.
我觉得 你该开一家餐馆
I think personally that you should open a restaurant.
嗯 做这个行当得会偷工减料
Well, the only way to make money in that business is to skim.
你会偷工减料搞餐饮吗
And you can't skim off yourself.
不 好吧 我的意思是 正常人谁会去
No, well, I mean, who in their right mind
搞餐饮?
goes into the restaurant business?
餐馆生意钱不好赚
There's no money in.. In the restaurant business.
一点也不好
None whatsoever.
你知道 你可不能有
You know, you have to divest yourself
这种想法啊 查理
of that notion, Charlie.
-嗯  -咋了?
-Uh  -huh.  -What?
看比赛 斯坦
Watch the game, Stan.
斯坦.穆林 我的老板
Stan Mullin, my boss.
他在比洛克希经营了47年
He's run Biloxi for 47 years.
他开始忘事已经有一段时间了
Been a while since he started forgetting things.
好的
Okay.
因此 我自告奋勇
So, I took it upon myself
来照顾他
to look out for him.
这是我欠他的
I owed him that.
我给你买了鱼油
I got you some fish oils!
富含欧米茄3
Omega threes.
对心脏有好处
Good for your heart.
剩菜都在冰箱里 饿了热热
Leftovers are in the fridge in case you're hungry later.
好的
Yeah.
-那孩子真可怜  -是啊 真遗憾
-Too bad about the kid.  -Yeah, it's a shame.
让小孩子做正事
What were you thinking,
你是咋想的?
letting a young kid like that do a job like that?
对不起 斯坦
I'm sorry, Stan.
不会再有了
Won't let it happen again.
-会有麻烦吗?  -不会
-We gonna have any trouble?  -No.
我已经处理好了
I took care of it.
-睡个好觉  -谢了 搭档
-Sleep well.  -Thanks, partner.
拜加.麦卡多
Beggar Mercado,
从小流氓混成了九街区老大
street thug turned Ninth Ward crew chief.
新一代的老大
One of the new breed of bosses
势力横扫新奥尔良
cutting a swathe through New Orleans.
看看货
Let's see.
干活儿的那家伙有点忘形
The guy who did him got a little carried away.
叫刀仔的小子 也许你认识他
Kid named Blade. Maybe you know him.
别着急 宝贝
Don't ring a bell, baby.
这是罗路?
And that's Rollo?
是他
It's him.
-在哪儿找到他的?  -用点力 哥们儿
-Where'd you find him?  -There you go, man.
机场边上的租屋
Rental, near the airport.
抓紧了?
Got him?
租约上写着他前妻的名字
With his ex's name on the lease.
蠢货
Dumb fuck.
-斯坦咋样了?  -斯坦还行
-How's Stan?  -Still Stan.
我曾想找他坐下来谈谈生意
I reached out to him for a sit  -down.
不过他没理我
He didn't reach back, though.
我的赚钱点子很多 他应该会喜欢的
I got a lot of ideas I know he'd like.
新地产
New construction,
新赌场、酒店
new casinos, hotels.
肥得很
Juicy territory.
你是他的人 劝劝他
You're his guy. Make it happen.
合作愉快?
We good?
啊
Ah.
这可是罗路第一次为我们的关系
First time Rollo's ever contributed anything
做出贡献
to this relationship.
谢谢
Thanks.
-顺便问问 你为啥不那么干?  -啥?
-By the way, why didn't you?  -What?
用胶带封住我的嘴 把我甩在罗路旁边?
Slap duct tape over my mouth, put me next to Rollo?
不是我的风格
Not my style.
另外 你做事不拖泥带水
Besides, you dealt with the situation straight up.
-这可不多见  -女人里很少见?
-Don' t see that often.  -From a woman?
任何人
From anybody.
嘿
Hey.
想吃点什么吗?
You wanna get something to eat?
-哇 这话从何说起?  -脱口而出的
-Wow, where'd that come from?  -My mouth.
未经过大脑
Which appears to have circumvented my brain,
就是这样
but there you have it.
为什么?
Why?
-庆祝一下  -庆祝什么 死了人?
-Celebrate.  -What, the dead guys?
问题解决了
Problem solved.
坏事避免了
Situation avoided.
还捡到钱了
Found money.
你选一个
You pick one.
-嗯 很美味  -还行
-Mm. Phenomenal.  -Good.
谁能想到这种叫"托斯卡纳番茄"的苍蝇小馆
Who'd have thunk you'd find something this divine
你都能找得到呢
at a place called Tuscan Tomato.
店主来自特雷维索(意大利)
Well, the owner's from Treviso.
叫克劳迪奥
A guy named Claudio.
英语不太好 但厨艺很棒
Not so good at English, but fantastic chef.
这 这是什么?
What's.. What.. What's in this?
马尔法蒂
Malfatti,
用意式干酪、面粉和焯过水的菠菜做的
ricotta, flour and, uh, blanched spinach.
你咋知道的?
And you know this how?
嗯 我喜欢做菜 知道吧?
Well, I just like to cook, you know?
业余爱好
That's kind of like a hobby for me.
-但主要是意大利菜  -为什么是意大利菜?
-But mostly Italian.  -Why Italian?
我在意大利呆过一段时间
Well, when I was stationed in Italy for a while there,
你知道 我也不清楚
you know, I don't know.
我爱上了那里的文化
I just fell in love with the culture.
喜欢意大利的一切
Love everything Italian.
动物标本是咋回事?
Why taxidermy?
那个嘛
All right.
我乐于给那些没有公平机会的生灵
I like giving everlasting life
赋予它们永恒的生命
to something that didn't have a fair chance at one.
-嗯  -我恢复了他们的尊严
-Hmm.  -I restore their dignity.
当我把猎物还给猎人时
When I give a hunter back his trophy,
我想让那只动物在他的梦中萦绕
I want that animal to haunt his dreams.
真是个有趣的职业
That's an intriguing profession.
不比被刽子手当枪使强多少
No more than being an enforcer for some mob.
-我不是刽子手  -那就是打手
-I'm not an enforcer.  -Muscle, then.
比我像打手的人多的是
Lot of guys with more muscle than me.
好吧
All right.
扣扳机的 按起爆键的
A trigger man, button guy.
我更像是一个 嗯 管家
I'm more like a, um, concierge.
-修理工  -解决问题的人
-A fixer.  -Problem solver.
嗯 就像...
Mm. Like...
有一具无头尸体需要辨认
I got a body with no head that needs identifying.
没错
Exactly.
就像我需要圣徒队
And if I needed tickets
前排座的票?
on the 50-yard line for a Saints game?
是的 我可以帮你拿
Yeah, I could get those for you.
你要杀了谁才能拿到?
Who would you have to kill to get 'em?
嗯 这要看他们的对手是谁了
Mm, depends on who they're playing.
嗯 给那家馆子评四颗星
Well, four stars for the Tuscan Tomato.
你觉得…
What do you think about...
你懂的
you know.
别想多了 查理
Don't think so much, Charlie.
享受当下吧 尽情享受
Stay in the moment. Enjoy it.
然后
The rest?
谁知道呢?
Who knows?
是啊 你在想啥呢 查理?
Yeah. What were you thinking, Charlie?
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
不要被他们油腻的大肚腩
Don't let the folds of fat hanging over their belts
和高高的发际线骗了
or their receding hairlines fool you.
建国三百年以来
There's over 300 years of state time standing there.
斯坦的手下
Stan's crew.
靠着敲诈勒索高利贷
Extortion, loan sharking.
无恶不作
You name it, they did it.
生日快乐 斯坦 生日快乐
Happy birthday, Stan. Happy birthday.
干掉他们 伙计 加油 宝贝 加油
Blow 'em out, buddy! Go baby, go!
我的族人 我爱他们
My family. Love 'em all.
开始吧 好了 班尼 这是你的
Here we go now. All right, Benny, there's yours.
-我他妈的可在节食啊 查理  -这我就不清楚了 班尼
-I'm on a fuckin' diet, Charlie.  -I don't know about that, Benny.
席琳可不是这么跟我说的
That's not what Celine tells me. Hoo  -hoo!
-好的  -谢谢 查理
-All right.  -Thank you, Charlie.
谢谢
Thank you.
班尼.莫林
Benny Morin.
管着斯坦所有的绅士俱乐部
Runs all of Stan's gentlemen's clubs.
他有一个原则 兔子不吃窝边草
Stuck to his one rule, never sample the wares.
那是他的妻子席琳
That's his wife, Celine.
历经28年 两人爱意愈浓
Those two more in love, 28 years later.
波利
Pauly.
斯坦当初以为他就是
Stan hired him thinking
波士顿的冰锥杀人狂波利
he was Pauly Ice Pick out of Boston.
可后来发现他其实并不是
When he found out he wasn't,
却不忍心把那孩子打发走
he couldn't bring himself to send the kid packing.
于是 他就让他做了自己的司机
So, he made him his chauffeur.
托尼.D
Tony D.
没有人知道这个D 代表什么
No one knows what the D stands for.
每个人都不敢问
Everyone's afraid to ask.
管理斯坦的赌博业
Runs Stan's gambling operations.
新妞儿 可别当面这么叫她
New Girl, only don't call her that to her face.
入行已经12年了
Been one of us for 12 years now.
我曾亲眼看到她砍掉一个人的大拇指
Saw her shoot a guy's big toe off
仅仅是因为这家伙叫了声她的绰号
when he forgot and called her that.
-蛋糕有点潮了  -超市买的
-Moist.  -Winn Dixie.
所以 我现在就只配吃点超市里买的生日蛋糕喽?
So, this is what I merit now, a store  -bought birthday cake?
是啊 蛋糕店里的那种
Yeah, those fancy bakery cakes.
看起来花哨
They look great.
味道渣得很
Taste like shit.
你回家吧 保罗
You go on home, Paul.
-我来收拾  -谢谢 查理
-I'll finish up here.  -Thanks, Charlie.
如果你想留下来看比赛的话
If you're gonna stay for the game,
别忘了晚上喂斯坦吃药
don't forget to give Stan his night pills.
不然他就会梦游
Otherwise, he sleep walks.
上星期他差点掉进泳池里
Last week, he almost walked into the pool.
再见 班尼
Later, Benny.
去吧
You got it.
对了
Yeah.
我在想
You know, I was thinking,
呃 你有没有 呃
uh, did you ever.. Uh,
买间那种漂亮的小房子?
did get one of those little, uh, pretty fixer uppers?
你知道 在你那个常去的地方?
You know, where you used to go all the time over there?
你一直往那边跑的地方
All the time, you'd go over there.
-意大利  -意大利 对 意大利
-Italy.  -Italy. Yeah. Yeah.
是的 不过我还在找
Yeah, no, I'm.. I'm still searching.
-干什么呢  -在找啊
-What are you doing?  -I'm searching.
-我还在找  -哦 还在找...
-I'm still looking.  -Oh, still search..
还找个屁啊
Fuck a bunch of searching.
买就完了
Just do it.
我现在要告诉你一件事
I'm gonna tell you something right now.
20年后
In 20 years from now,
你会对你想做但没有做的事情
you'll be much more disappointed at the things you didn't do then
更加失望
than the ones you did.
这就是如今这天下唯一值得一提
Now, that's the only law of the universe
的规律
that's worth a shit.
嗯 有道理
Well, there's a truth in that.
你看我 我都准备好了
Look at me. I'm set.
我在海湾公园有块地
I got a place in Gulf Park
退休之后养养小马
I'm gonna spend my sunset days watching them ponies.
白天和小马玩
Playing 'em during the day
晚上再喝点朗姆酒
and some rum punches at night.
你知道 这听起来像一个计划
You know, now, that sounds like a plan.
计划 计划可赶不上变化
Plan, you want.. You want God to laugh, you make a plan.
-拜加  -什么?
-Beggar.  -Huh?
拜加想和你坐下来谈谈
Beggar wants a sit  -down with you.
他为什么要和我坐下来谈?
What does he want a sit  -down with me for?
他想和你谈谈他的想法
He wants to run some ideas by you.
他会有什么想法?
What kind of ideas might he have?
不知道 我也不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
他说他联系过你
He said he reached out to you.
是吗 他是想搞什么新花样?
Well, what, does he got something?
也许吧
Maybe.
行吧
All right.
我来告诉你我怎么应对
I'll tell you what. Go ahead and set it up.
我要让他坐在我面前
I'm gonna sit him right in front of me,
然后叫他去死
this close, and I'll tell him to go fuck himself.
你瞧 老话说得好
See, here's the thing that I did learn, though,
人是不能和猪共圈的
that you don't wrestle with a pig.
不仅会把你弄脏 而猪还乐在其中
It'll get you dirty, and he'll like it.
好的
Okay.
All right.
离那个混混远点
Stay away from that bum.
"我想你应该会喜欢这个挑战--查理"
别紧张
Easy, now.
你们这些蠢货进门不会按门铃的吗?
You dumb fucks ever heard of Ring doorbell?
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
抓起他
Get him.
继续 抓住他 搬起来
Go on. Get him. Pick him up.
我是班尼 请留言
You've reached Benny, leave a message.
嘿 班尼 我们被攻击了
Hey, Benny, we're under attack.
警告赌场里的每个人
Warn everyone at the casino.
快点
Come on.
你好 斯坦.穆伦的家
Hi, this is Stan Mullens.
请留言
Please leave a message.
他是个快乐的好伙伴 他是个快乐的好伙伴
For he's a jolly good fellow For he's a jolly good fellow
谁也无法否认 谁也无法否认
Which nobody can deny Which nobody can deny
他是个快乐的好伙伴
For he's A jolly good fellow
谁也无法否认
Which nobody can deny
你们喜欢海鸥吧?
You like gulls, don't you?
当然
Sure do.
去看看吧
Let's go check it out.
要不你们去喂喂海鸥吧?
Why don't you go feed the seagulls, huh?
谢谢
Thanks.
别喂太多
Not too generous.
我们走吧
Let's go.
看来你让孙女来探望你了
I see you got the granddaughter visiting.
我猜你是想杀拜加
I assume you want to kill Beggar.
你知道我不会允许
You know I can't sanction that.
你允许了对斯坦的袭击
You sanctioned a hit on Stan.
不 我没有
No, I did not.
那是瞎胡闹 没人知道
That was a rogue move. Nobody knew.
那问题出在哪里?
Then, what's the issue?
拜加能赚钱
Beggar's an earner.
源源不断地为组织赚钱
Funnels a lot of money into the coffers.
时代变了
And to stay vital,
你得转换一下你的思维方式
you gotta change your way of thinking.
一代新人换旧人嘛
Make room for the new guys.
斯坦以公平待你
Stan was always fair with you.
可斯坦走了
Stan's gone.
机灵点 你也该走了
And you should be, too, if you're smart.
我保证不会有人动你
I'm offering you that.
我一直有个原则 赛尔
I've always had one rule, Sal.
善待对你好的人
Be good to the people who were good to you.
那就对自己好点 查理
Then be good to yourself, Charlie,
离开这里 越远越好
and get as far away from here as you can.
要知道
Understand,
如果你杀了拜加…
if you kill Beggar..
嘿 我来这里是出于对你的尊重
Hey. I came here out of respect.
想做什么就做吧
You do what you have to do.
-罗路有拜加的什么把柄?  -我不知道
-What did Rollo have on Beggar?  -I don't know.
但不管是什么 他都死了
But whatever it was got him deceased.
他在哪儿 拜加?
Where is he, Beggar?
要不去问问你的手下?
Why don't you ask one of your crew?
我也想
I would.
但他们都死了
But they're all dead.
你确定?
You sure about that?
好吧 班尼
All right, Benny,
这是你的 给你 席琳
there's yours, here you go, Celine.
-谢谢 查理  -你见过刀仔吗?
-Thanks, Charlie.  -You seen Blade?
嗯?
Hmm?
知道刀仔去哪了吗?
You seen Blade?
我看起来像他的假释官吗?
Do I look like his parole officer?
查理.斯威夫特
Charlie Swift.
席琳
Uh, Celine.
-班尼在吗?  -你刚错过了他
-Is Benny around?  -You just missed him.
他去俱乐部见几个人
He went to go meet some guys over at the club.
我等下他打电话 告诉他你来过
I was just gonna call him. I'll tell him you stopped by.
我总爱在他上班前和他道别
I always say goodbye to him before work.
我俩的小亲密
It's just our thing.
但不知为何 今天没有
Didn't say it today for some reason.
告诉他 我是认真的
You tell him I meant to.
背叛是件有趣的事
Betrayal's a funny thing.
它的本质就是让你措手不及
Its very nature is to catch you unaware.
这是我始料未及的一记重拳
This one was a gut punch I never saw coming.
-嘿 查理  -嘿 吉塞尔
-Hey, Charlie.  -Hey, Giselle.
明天我下班后你来吗?
You comin' over after my shift tomorrow?
我可能得改天再来了
I might have to take a rain check.
来之前我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
-查理  -米尔特
-Charlie.  -Milt.
我还以为你只管招人
I thought you were doing collections.
-而不是当保安  -对 坐上来
-Not bouncer work.  -Right, sit on it.
-这地方换新老板了  -来吧 再来一下
-Place is under new management.  -Come on, one more.
-拜加的人已经接管了?  -不错嘛
-Beggar's guys already move in?  -Nice.
灯光一亮
Soon as the lights came on.
-哦 摇起来 -像蟑螂一样
-Ooh! Give me some shake!  -Like roaches.
听说你搬回去和埃斯特在一起了
You moved in with Esther, I hear.
我打赌她会很高兴看到你
I bet you she'd be glad to see you come home
早点回家吃晚饭的
early for supper.
我回去时给她买点鸡翅
I'll bring her some wings.
也许会中奖也说不定
Maybe I'll get lucky.
大吉大利 拿好收据
Don't forget to get a receipt.
对 就这样
Yeah, that's it!
就这样 哇哦
That's it! Whoo!
查理 不 不
Charlie. No. No.
查理 拜加说斯坦玩完了
Charlie, Beggar said Stan was finished here.
他变了 查理
He wasn't the same, Charlie.
他的想法并不总是对的
He wasn't always right in the head.
你是主动背叛的
You turned on your own.
我得为自己的将来考虑
I had to make a choice for myself.
拜加在哪里?
Where's Beggar?
他从开始就一直在行动
He's been on the move since this thing went down.
疯了似的到处找那个叫罗路的家伙身上的东西
Out of his fuckin' mind, looking for whatever that Rollo guy had on him.
他整个帮派都在找
He's got the whole gang looking for it.
你应该离开比洛克希 查理
You ought to get out of Biloxi, Charlie.
每个人都这么跟我说
That's what everyone keeps telling me.
哦 宝贝
Ooh, baby!
埃斯特喜欢很晚才吃饭
Esther likes to eat late.
克莱默小姐
Miss Kramer.
你好 斯威夫特先生
Hello, Mr. Swift.
我打电话来是想告诉你 谢谢你的礼物
Just calling to say thanks for your lovely gift.
我希望能周末能接他回家
I was hoping to get him home for the weekend.
我有一只雪貂
I have a ferret
还有一只白尾鹰排在你前面
and a white tailed eagle ahead of yours,
所以你的小朋友得等等了
so your little friend's gonna have to wait.
对了 你在哪儿找到他的?
By the way, where'd you find him?
欧几里得街和格兰德街的东南角
Southeast corner of Euclid and Grand.
-他有名字吗?  -嗯 叫洛基
-He got a name?  -Uh  -huh. Rocky.
很特别的名字
Original.
嗯 它是浣熊中的铁匠
Well, it's the Smith of raccoons.
我准备花多一点时间帮他
I'm gonna need a little more time with him,
做个头饰
due to the tire marks.
不着急
Take your time.
-我只想给洛基最好的  -没问题
-I just want the best for Rocky.  -You got it.
丈夫和妻子
Husband and wife
操蛋的人生
Your whole fucking life
我们不必在一起
We won't be together
因为你值得…
'Cause you deserve..
为老家伙的事生气?
Pissed about the old man?
那伙计已经过了"保质期"
Guy was past his "sell by" date.
托尼 找到包裹了吗?
Tony, did you find the package?
别找了
Stopped lookin'.
快枪查理
Fast Charlie.
厉害啊
I am impressed.
他可是我第二棒的手下
He was my second  -best guy.
嗯 期待你的头号手下
Well, looking forward to meeting number one.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
你 已经死了
You, not breathing.
你打算怎么做?
And how are you gonna do that?
我正做着
I'm doing it.
哦 那你还有很长的路要走 我的朋友
Oh, you got a long way to go, my friend.
我的人比你的子弹还多
I got more men than you got bullets.
赔率对你不利
Odds ain't in your favor.
子弹很容易搞到
Bullets are easy to get.
人嘛 我不太确定
Men, I'm not so sure.
或者 我可以找出罗路之前弄到了你的
Or I could find out what Rollo had on you
什么把柄
before you do.
咋样?
How's that sound?
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
给我把那个怪胎找出来
Get me the freak.
"去找罗路的前妻"
我不断翻阅过往日记
I keep on Turning these pages I write
感觉一直在等你
Feels like I've waited for you...
日日又夜夜
And these days Become nights
我要找出一个解
And I'm trying To find a way
放轻松 放轻松
Easy, now. Just be easy.
告诉我们东西在哪里
Just tell us where it's at,
免得把这里越弄越乱
keep your place from getting more fucked up.
我说过好多遍了 不知道
I'd be repeating myself.
要不要我讲慢点 或者画给你看明白
I could say it slower, or I could draw you a picture.
我不知道你在找什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
这是什么鸟?
The fuck kinda bird is this?
-长嘴啄木鸟  -什么?
-Long billed woodcock.  -Yeah?
姑娘 我身上有只大啄木鸟
Girl, I got a big ole woodcock on me.
对一个12岁的小孩来说 还挺聪明
That's real clever, for a 12  -year  -old.
能把它放下吗 我已经做了30个小时了
Can you put that down, I've been working on it for 30 hours already.
他怎么了? 被卡车撞了?
What happened to him? He got hit by a truck?
一个混蛋用鸟枪打的
Some shithead loaded it with birdshot.
没看到弹洞啊
I don't see no birdshot.
没看到? 这不就是
No? Look here.
翻过来
Turn it over.
就在那儿
Right there.
来的不是时候?
This a bad time?
该死的天主教徒
Fucking Catholic.
现在我明白你为什么喜欢那辆老爷车了
Now I see why you like that old man car.
罗路来过
Rollo was here.
他比你早来四天
He showed up about four days before you did.
他跟我说 如果我帮他租个隐蔽点的 专门用来
Told me he'd give me 50 grand if I would help him rent
坑蒙拐骗的房子 他就会给我五万块
a place to lay low while he was working some shakedown scheme.
我跟他说 做这种事情会遭报应的 你瞧瞧
I told him the whole thing was gonna blow up in his face, and it did.
没说错吧
Literally.
现在怎么办?
What now?
好吧 我先处理掉这些尸体
Well, I'm gonna dump these guys,
再去新奥尔良 罗路的地盘
then head to New Orleans, Rollo's home turf.
他们要找的东西肯定就在那里
Pretty sure whatever they're looking for is there.
可能就在我的五万块旁边
Probably right next to my 50 grand.
-我觉得这不是个好主意  -你有更好的主意吗?
-I don't think that's a good idea.  -Do you have a better idea?
-你想让我做什么? 坐在酒店房间里?  -我不…
-What would you have me do? Sit in some hotel room?  -I don't..
等你告诉我安全了吗?
Wait for you to tell me the coast is clear?
-万一你先挂了呢?  -呃…
-What if you get killed first?  -Well..
然后 有一天我醒来 发现又多了一个马特和杰夫
And then, I wake up one day, and there's another Mutt and Jeff
在我的床脚 拿着胶带和手枪?
at the foot of my bed holding duct tape and 45s?
另外 你知道罗路住哪里吗?
Besides, do you have any idea where Rollo lived,
他在哪里出没 和他混的都是哪些蠢货?
where he hung out, the morons he rolled with?
我知道 那五万块钱可以改变我的生活
I do. That 50 grand could really change things for me.
不管有没有你 我都要找到它
I'm gonna find it, with or without you.
轻装上阵吧
Pack light.
那么 这五万块
So, this 50 grand,
如果找到了 你打算怎么处理?
what are you gonna do with it if you find it, anyway?
位于巴吞鲁日的路易斯安那州立大学
LSU campus in Baton Rouge,
有一间自然历史博物馆
they have a Natural History Museum.
他们说想聘用我
Uh, they said that they would like to hire me
担任鸟类展馆的馆长
to be the director of avian exhibits.
-嗯 当教授  -不 不完全是
-Hmm. Professor.  -No, not quite.
他们喜欢我的作品
But they like my work.
说只要我拿到证书 工作就是我的了
Said if I got certified, the job was mine.
两万的培训课程
Twenty thousand pays for the course,
五千块的搬家费
five thousand in moving expenses,
其余的作为起步资金
and the rest for a starter place.
另外 换换环境对我也有好处
Plus, a change of scenery would be good for me.
新的开始
New start.
你呢? 你有什么计划吗?
What about you? You have any plans when this is over?
就我的工作而言 最好不要有什么长期计划
My line of work, it's best not to have any long  -term plans.
但你总得考虑考虑吧
You must think about something.
嗯
Mm  -hmm.
"新奥尔良 路易斯安那州"
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey!
-这是什么地方?  -一个无人知晓的地方
-What is this?  -A place nobody knows.
不过 好歹有间厨房
However, it does have a kitchen.
-嗯?  -真好吃
-Mm?  -So good.
嗯嗯
Hmm. Yeah.
所以 拜加
So, Beggar,
他决定采取行动 将所有人一网打尽
he decides to make his move, and he wipes everyone out.
你是最后一个还活着的?
You end up being the last man standing?
看上去可能是吧
Well, it would appear that way.
那你为什么不跑?
Well, why didn't you run?
斯坦.穆伦 我的老板 33年的朋友
Stan Mullen, my boss, my friend of 33 years.
一个循规蹈矩 信守诺言的人
A man who played by the rules, kept his word,
人缘也好
did well by people.
他值得以自己的方式离开
He deserved to go out on his terms,
但他没能做到
only he didn't get to.
斯坦死了 查理
Stan's dead, Charlie.
为什么他对你这么重要?
Why does this mean so much to you?
我五岁的时候
When I was five,
我会在门口等爸爸回家
I'd wait at the door for my pops to come home.
我戴着牛仔帽 穿着靴子 拿着枪
My cowboy hat on, my boots on, my gun on.
他一进来 我会给他一把枪 然后他就会说"拔枪"
He'd come in, I'd give him a gun, and he'd say "draw."
很明显 一个二十五六岁的男人
Now, obviously, a 25, 26-year-old man's
能轻易赢过一个五岁的孩子
gonna beat a five-year-old kid to the draw.
但让我烦恼的是
But what bothered me was...
每天...
that every day...
每一天 他都会把我打得落花流水
every single day, he'd beat me to the draw.
他会让我把手举起来
He'd make me put my hands up in the air,
转过身 面对墙壁
turn round and face the wall.
然后从背后朝我开枪
Then he'd shoot me in the back.
天天如此
Every day, he did that.
然后 有一天 我反抗了 并问他
Then, one day, I reared up and I said,
"反正你总是要开枪打我
you know, "What's the sense of facing the wall
为什么总是要我冲着墙呢?"
if you're gonna shoot me in the back?"
于是他说 "好吧 也许今天 我不会开枪"
And he said, "Well, maybe today, I won't."
于是 我转过身 面对墙壁 然后
So, I turn around, face the wall, and...
他从背后向我开了枪
...shot me in the back.
我恨他
Hated him.
现在 有一天晚上...
Now, one night...
一天晚上 我把这件事告诉斯坦 他说
...one night, I tell this to Stan, and he says,
"他回家的时候 你应该在等他
"When he came home, you should be waiting for him.
他一进来 你就应该
Soon as he came in, you should've been hiding
躲在门后朝他开枪
behind the door, and shot him in the back.
我的意思是 给他妈的一枪 给他妈的一个机会"
I mean, fuck giving him a gun, and fuck giving him a chance."
他说 "生活中 你可以按照别人的规则行事
He says, "In life, you can play by someone else's rules"
或者你也可以自己定义规则
or you can play by your own.
照别人的规则行事
You play by someone else's rules,
每次都会完蛋
you're gonna get fucked every time
因为这是他们的设计 不是你的"
"'cause it's their design, not yours."
我老爸只是想给我上一课
My old man was just trying to teach me a lesson.
斯坦让我明白了这一点
Stan got me to see that.
嗯 很重要
Hmm. Lifted the weight
三十多年来 我一直铭记于心
I carried in my heart for 30 years.
我去点个午餐
I'm gonna order some lunch.
真爱归真爱
True love to true love
铁锈归铁锈
Rust to rust
八年了 我要他修一修
Eight years, I asked him to fix the boards
步道上的木板
on that walkway.
懒得要死
Always was a lazy fuck.
努力做个好孩子
Trying to be a good boy
风中有变
Something changes In the wind
你们是怎么走到一起的?
How did you two get together?
哦 那个
Oh, yeah.
总有脆弱的时候
Moment of weakness.
-我当时32岁 你懂的  -嗯哼
-I was 32 and, you know.  -Mm  -hmm.
持续了多久?
How long?
直到我意识到他是个
'Til I realized that he was always one scheme away
自甘堕落的垃圾为止
from ending up in your trash swamp.
克莱默先生 您点的餐
Mr. Kramer! Food delivery!
有人吗? 有人在家吗?
Hello? Anyone home?
午餐到了
Lunch is served.
拜加的人
After Beggar's guys
把这里翻了个底朝天
turned the place upside down and inside out,
我不指望能在这里找到罗路的那张王牌
I didn't expect to find Rollo's ace card.
只希望能找到他隐藏起来的线索
I just hoped to find a clue as to where he stashed it.
你到底在找什么?
What exactly are you looking for?
红色带锁的箱子 这么大 上面有野马车的图案
Red lockbox, yea big. Picture of a mustang on it.
那是他存放贵重物品的东西
That's where he kept his valuables.
我见过这种表情
I knew that look.
当我开始这种生活的时候 在清冷的早晨
I've seen it in the mirror a few cold mornings
我在镜子里看到过的自己 也是这幅表情
back when I started this life.
真正让人难以释怀的
It's not really letting go of the past
并非过去
that sticks with you.
而是放弃自己
It's coming to terms with letting go of the future
永远不会到来的未来
that will never be.
它会一直伴随着你
It stays with you.
无论你躲得多远
No matter how far you run from it.
你确定要留下来?
You sure you wanna stay?
我想把所有东西都看一遍
I wanna finish going through everything.
都是些我离开时他不让我拿的东西
Just the stuff he wouldn't let me have when I took off.
我等下自己叫个优步回去
I'll take an Uber back to your place.
头等舱酒店
AirLine Inn.
-喂 下午好  -下午好 先生
-Yes, good afternoon there.  -Oh, good afternoon, Sir.
我是克莱默先生 您好 下午好
My name is Mr.  Kramer. Yes, good afternoon to you.
听着 麻烦你 我想查查我的房费
Listen, I'd like to check on my room charges, please.
但我好像忘记账单放哪儿了
But I seem to have misplaced my bill.
如果您愿意 我可以把账单送到您的房间
If you'd like, I can send a current bill up to your room.
哦 那就太感谢了
Oh, that would be so much appreciated.
你能顺便叫个维修人员吗?
Could you send maintenance up there,
检查下厕所
please, check on my toilet?
你知道 不停在冲水
You know, just keeps running and running.
当然 704房间 马上来
Of course. Room 704. Coming up.
嘿
Hey!
没啥问题啊
Couldn't find anything.
我把阀门拧紧了 似乎有效 所以
I tightened your valve. Seems to be working, so...
谢谢 给
Thanks, man. Here you go.
该死的玩意 让我整晚睡不着
Damn thing kept me up all night.
-祝您愉快  -好的
-Have a good day.  -You got it.
洗衣滑道
见鬼
Shit.
所有入住酒店的客人请注意
Attention, all hotel guests!
酒店内有一名持枪枪手
There is an active shooter in the hotel.
请隐蔽好自己
Please seek shelter.
在另行通知之前 请锁好房门
Keep your room door locked until further notice.
酒店内有一名持枪枪手
There's an active shooter in the hotel.
在另行通知之前 请锁好房门
Keep your room door locked until further notice.
-查理?  -是我.
-Charlie?  -Yeah.
天啊 查理
Jesus, Charlie.
-到底发生了什么事?  -我中枪了
-What the hell happened?  -I got shot.
-谁干的?  -哦 某个家伙
-By who?  -Oh, some guy.
家伙? 你是说像你这样的人
A guy? A guy like you, you mean.
嗯 这个不一样 很厉害
Mm. This one was different. Deluxe model.
拜加的头号杀手
Beggar's number one.
可能是你的脑袋进水了 查理
Could be you're in over your head, Charlie.
运气至今为止都还不错
Been doing all right up until today.
罗路也是一样 直到他挂掉的时候
Rollo was doing all right 'til he wasn't.
别想着在我
Don't get any ideas
流血而死之前去告发我
about stuffing me before I bleed to death.
我不会的
I wouldn't.
不会?
No?
为什么不呢?
Why not?
我看不懂你
I couldn't capture your essence.
但你看得懂浣熊
You capture a raccoon's essence.
你是一个完全不同的生物
You're an entirely different creature.
嗯 嗯 这当然
Hm. Well, that's for sure.
哦 看在上帝的份上 查理 给
Oh, for God sake's, Charlie. Here.
你知道 你真的应该开始考虑退出计划了
You know, you really oughta start thinking about an exit plan.
一个退休的地方
A place to retire,
假设你对此事有发言权的话
assuming you'll have a say in the matter.
我正在考虑买一个
I was thinking about buying one of these.
嗯
Hmm.
只卖一美元
They go for a dollar.
当然 你得保证你会修缮好
Of course, you only have to promise that you'll fix them up.
但你知道 真的很美
But, you know, it's beautiful.
这个在翁布里亚(意大利)
This one's in Umbria.
我的意思是 这些东西在意大利俯首皆是
I mean, you can find these all over Italy.
-你找了多久?  -几年了
-How long you been looking?  -Couple of years.
你还在等什么? 等降价到50美分吗?
Well, what are you waiting for? For them to go down to 50 cents?
这是个美梦 查理
It's a beautiful dream, Charlie.
你应该去试试
You oughta go for it.
嗯
Hmm.
是啊
Yeah.
我以前在哪里听说过
I heard that somewhere before once.
有什么好笑的?
What's funny?
罗路被人悬赏 正在逃命
Rollo's got a price on his head and is running for his life.
不过 他还是从酒店给他妈妈打了三次电话
Still, he calls his mama three times from the hotel.
这不是"娼妓小姐"吗?
Well, if it isn't "Ms. Whores R Us."
-你他妈是谁?  -他是罗路的朋友
-Who the fuck are you?  -He's a friend of Rollo's.
看起来不像他的朋友
Doesn't look like any of his friends.
最近有人来过吗?
Any come by recently?
你说过我接我儿子朋友的客要价很低这种话吧?
You claimin' I entertain my son's friends here for a small fee?
-后面有个棚子 他的私人空间  -别碰他的东西
-There's a shed out back he uses as his man cave.  -Don't you touch his shit!
好吧 在哪儿?
All right. Where is it?
-什么?  -锁箱在哪
-What?  -The lockbox.
在你的屁眼里吧 偷儿的玩意儿
Probably up your gaping asshole, son stealer.
那不是你的东西 你这个臭婊子
That ain't your property, you testicle sucker.
里面有什么 他答应给我的
What's in it, he promised to me.
如果他想让你拥有它
If he wanted you to have it,
他会把它塞进你的屁眼
he'd have shoved it up your cooch.
主知道它大到足够装得下
Lord knows it's big enough.
还记得我结婚那天吗 梅维斯
Remember my wedding day, Mavis?
你一只手手拎着百威啤酒到处跑
You were running around with a Budweiser in one hand
另一只手则牵着弗雷德叔叔的老二
and your Uncle Fred's dick in the other.
7月29日 7 2 9
July 29, seven, two, nine.
你期望能在里面找到什么?
What'd you expect to find in there?
5万块 都是20和50面额的旧钞
50 grand? In unmarked 20s and 50s?
-哪儿去了?  -你正看着呢
-Where is it?  -You're looking at it.
每只两万五
25K each.
-双D罩杯  -哦 老天爷
-Double Ds.  -Oh, God.
乳头跟银元那么大
Nipples the size of silver dollars now.
抱歉 你没了五万块
I'm sorry about your 50K.
是啊 从一开始就没戏
Yeah, well, it was a long shot from the get  -go.
至少你的光盘还在某个地方
At least your disc is still out there somewhere.
-嗯  -而我的则变成了一对双D杯的奶子
-Mm  -hmm.  -Mine turned into a pair of double Ds.
当然
Sure did.
啊 我真该一见到他就把门摔在他脸上
Augh, I should've slammed the door in his face the moment I saw him.
你不禁要问 我到底是怎么了?
You gotta wonder what's wrong with me that I didn't.
放下希望很难
It's hard to let go of hope.
我必须学会放下很多东西
I gotta learn to let go of a lot of things.
好像汽车站就在几个街区外
Looks like the bus station's just a few blocks.
你可以把我放在那儿
You can, uh, drop me there.
是啊
Yeah.
你打算怎么办?
What you gonna do?
生存下来
Survive.
我们要么让自己痛苦 要么让自己更强大
We can either make ourselves miserable or make ourselves stronger.
工作量是一样的
The amount of work is the same.
你?
You?
哦 我想我会继续找的
Oh, I suppose I'll keep looking.
-我不喜欢散漫的结局
-Why?  -I don't like loose ends.
啊 Ah.希望你找到之前他们不会杀了你
Ah. I hope they don't kill you before you find it, then.
谢谢我很感谢你的心意
Thank you. I appreciate the sentiment.
哦 不我从这里拿到的 查理
Oh, no. I got it from here, Charlie.
-这是贷款 好吗?  -不 请不要
-It's a loan, okay?  -No, please don't.
-玛茜 只是...听着 贷款意味着
-Marcie, just..  -No. Look, a loan means
你会回来找我的
you're gonna be coming back for me.
然后我就想知道你到底有没有成功
And then I gotta wonder if you made it or not.
然后我希望你不要改变主意
And then I gotta hope you didn't change your mind.
-我现在就可以告诉你 我会 查理 别这样
-I can tell you right now that I'll..  -Charlie, don't.
这里 呃 就在那边的几个街区
Here, it's just, uh, just a couple blocks that way.
是啊
Yeah.
听着 你有事情要做...
Look, you got something you gotta do...
从那时到现在 可能会发生很多事情
and a lot can happen between then and now.
就放在这里吧 好吗?
Let's just leave it here, okay?
别爱上我 查理  -斯威夫特
Don't you be in love with me, Charlie Swift.
太迟了
Too late.
我知道你的东西在哪里
I know where your thing is.
拜加酒吧罗路曾经管理过它
Beggar's bar. Rollo used to manage it.
他对我说的最后一句话是 就在他们眼皮底下
Last thing he said to me was it's right under their noses.
好了明白了吗?
All right. Got it?
他在哪儿 罗尼?那只黄鼠狼呢?
Where is he, Ronnie? Where's that weasel?
-我知道他就藏在这里的某个地方  -玛茜
-I know he's hiding here somewhere.  -Marcie.
-他躲在哪里?  -嗯 罗路?
-Where is he hiding?  -Um, Rollo?
-玛茜 罗路的妻子 你是个大骗子
-Marcie, Rollo's dea..  -You're a shitty liar.
你一直都是你在后面吗 罗路
You always were. You back there, Rollo?
你再拿枪指着我 我就把它塞进你的屁眼！
You pull a gun on me again, and I'll shove it up your ass!
你躲在哪里 你这个废物?
Where are you hiding, you piece of shit?
你在上面睡觉?什么?
You were sleeping up there? Huh?
拜托 我还有账单要付呢
Come on, I got bills to pay!
来吧
Come on!
面对我 你这个懦夫
Face me, you coward!
联邦调查局 路易斯安纳州梅泰里 第23-74号案件证据
等那个傻逼来了 你告诉他
If you see that cum stain, you tell him
要他给我五万块 否则我就切掉他的老二
he better give me my 50 grand, or I'll cut his dick off.
-等等 急什么 玛茜?  -拜加应该是在找你
-Wait, what's the rush, Marcie?  -I think Beggar's looking for you.
-滚开  -麻烦等一下 我给他打个电话?
-Fuck off me!  -Won't you hang tight while I give him a call?
放开我 你个混蛋
Let me go, you dick!
离这位女士远点
Step away from the lady.
我没看到什么女士
I don't see no lady here.
再看看
Look again.
哇 哇 哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
手 慢慢来 这就对了
Hands, now, hands, hands. Nice and easy. There you go.
你回安全屋
You go back to the safe house.
我来搞定这群家伙
I'll disable this crew.
好的 帮我拿着这个
Yeah. Hold onto this for me.
很好 起来
Nice and easy. Up.
给我起来
Get your ass up!
进吧台里面
Back up into the bar.
跪下
Down. Get on your knees. Get on your knees!
现在 你们这群杂碎里面有谁会数到十吗?
Now, can any of you dumb fucks count to ten?
因为我就有这么多子弹
'Cause that's how many rounds I have.
这意味着你们中间有一个人
Which means one of you
也许能活着离开
might just get out of here alive.
只有你会死
Only one that's gonna get deceased is you.
虽然我很想就地把你崩了 让这群傻逼来擦你的脑浆子
I'd do you right here, let these fucking clowns clean up the mess,
但拜加却想亲手丢你喂鳄鱼
but Beggar wants to feed you to the gators himself.
只有你和他
Just you and him.
他有很多事情想问问你
He'll have a lot to chew on.
你就是拜加的头号杀手?
You exclusive to Beggar?
下一个出口
Next exit.
他死了吗?
Is he dead?
我报警了
I'm calling the cops...
来吧 玛茜 来吧
Come on, Marcie. Come on.
我是玛茜.克莱默 标本制作师
This is Marcie Kramer, taxidermist.
-请留言  -操
-Please leave your message.  -Shit.
喂 玛茜? 你还好吗?
Yes, Marcie? Are you okay?
你不会死的 对吗?
You just won't die, will you?
老狗日的
Your old dumping grounds.
在我射爆她的头之前 你还有一小时
You got one hour before I shoot her in the head.
你个臭狗屎
You piece of fucking shit.
站那儿别动
Stop right there!
把手放在我能看到的地方
Put your hands where I can see them.
我一直认为我会被一颗
Always thought my life would end like this.
莫名而来的子弹了却残生
From a bullet I didn't see coming.
脱下衬衫
Shirt off!
我只是从没想过我会在乎
I just never thought I'd care.
其实 我很在乎
Only, I did care.
我没事 查理 别担心
I'm okay, Charlie. Don't worry.
裤子也脱了
Pants off!
快点 狗娘养的
Come on, motherfucker.
所以 我不得不在既没有袖口
So, I was gonna have to pull off a magic trick
也没有裤子的情况下
with nothing up my sleeve
完成魔术表演了
or down my pants.
把手举起来
Keep your hands up!
慢点转身
Turn around! Slow!
不可能 对吧?
Impossible, right?
好吧 好吧 放轻松
Okay, okay, okay. Take it easy.
十五秒内把光盘给我
Fifteen seconds to give me that disc.
再想想
Think again.
先看看她
Her first.
下一枪就打脖子
The next one's in her neck.
-十秒  -我要知道她没事
-Ten!  -I need to know she's okay.
-这是咋回事?  -这婊子不肯听我的话跟我过来呗
-What happened?  -Bitch didn't come quietly when I asked her to.
-你没事吧?  -把光盘给他吧
-You okay?  -Just give him the disc.
我在想意大利的房子 买了要修缮的那些房子
I was thinking about the houses, the fixer  -uppers in Italy.
为什么我一直犹豫不定?
Why I didn't pull the trigger on one.
我是在等某个人和我一起去看
I was waiting for someone to come with me.
你懂的 这样的美梦
You know, didn't see the point in...
只有我一个人做的话 很无趣
living that kind of dream all alone.
还有五秒钟 情圣
You got five seconds, Romeo!
光盘可以给你
You can have the disc.
只有一个小麻烦
Only, there's a small problem.
有麻烦的人可不是我
I ain't the one with the problem.
是的 就是你
Yeah, you are.
萨尔在巴吞鲁日(路易斯安那州府)的手下之一
One of Sal's dudes in Baton Rouge,
周二晚上会带一批货来
bringing in some shit on Tuesday night.
这是送货的船名
Here's the name of the boat it's coming in on.
多年前我就已向联邦调查局举报你了
Been ratting you out to the Feds for years.
我之是他的赚钱工具
I'm his money maker.
我要把他们一点一点剥皮啖肉
I'm gonna take this shit down piece by piece,
直到我上位
'til I'm the man.
我得和萨尔商量一下
I had to run it by Sal,
确保他能接受我杀你
make sure he was okay with me killing you.
玛茜?
Marcie?
你鞋上是什么?
What's that on your shoe?
哦！
Oh!
非常感谢 米尔特
Much appreciated, Milt.
永远忠诚(海军陆战队口号) 兄弟
Semper fi, brother.
抱歉给你带来的这些不快
Sorry about the drama.
好了 解开了
Here you go, get you untied.
都开了
All good.
-那是谁?  -哦 谁也不是
-Who's that?  -Oh, nobody.
哦 等等 这是什么?
Oh. Wait, what's this?
好吧 这是一个开始
Well, it's a start.
意大利产的(菲亚特)
It's Italian.
真爱归真爱 铁锈归铁锈
True love to true love And rust to rust
我让别人扔石头 自己却在尘土中作画
I let the others cast stones While I drew in the dust
我想做个好人
I tried to be a good man
风中有变
Something changes In the wind
我得到了古老的黑魔法
I got that old black magic
就在此地
Right over here.
施放开来
Rolling in
格林先生 有人要见你 先生
Mr. Greene, someone's here to see you, Sir.
这一注下的挺到位
That's a smart bet right there.
-我操 查理  -你好啊
-That's fucking Charlie.  -Hey there.
你去哪儿了? 我一直在给你打电话
Where you been? I've been calling you.
我知道 我知道 我 呃...
I know, I know, I know, I, uh...
我一直在处理这件事
I been taking care of that business
-我们谈过的 斯坦  -斯坦?
-we talked about, Stan.  -Stan?
你不是说你是最后一个吗?
I thought you said you were the last one.
好吧 我说过可能是
Well, I said it would appear that way.
司机保利中弹身亡
Paulie, the chauffeur, got off his shot.
验尸官办公室的一位老朋友处理了剩下的事情
An old pal at the coroner's office took care of the rest.
斯坦.穆伦正式死亡
Stan Mullen was officially dead.
那 她是谁?
Now, who is she?
这是玛茜
This is Marcie.
-玛茜?  -我是查理的朋友
-Marcie?  -I'm a friend of Charlie's.
你想听故事吗?
You wanna hear something?
现在
Now...
你知道 我 我 我 我不知道...
You know, I.. I.. I.. I don't know..
我不知道我是怎么来到这里的
I don't know how I got here.
-真的吗?
-Really?  -Yeah.
我们那会儿正在看球赛
We were watching the game.
现在 你不能与猪同圈
Now, you don't wrestle with a pig.
不仅会把你弄脏 而猪还乐在其中
He'll get you dirty, and he'll like it.
-好的  -离那个混混远点
-All right.  -Stay away from that bum.
不是好鸟
No good.
要不我来来一次小小的公路旅行吧
Why don't we take a little road trip?
-哇哦.  -耶 看看这个
-Wow.  -Yeah. Look at this.
很不错
It's pretty nice.
当然 你花钱了
It oughta be. You bought and paid for it.
把他的药放在厨房的桌子上
Put his meds on the kitchen table.
-早上吃三片  -我知道的 查理
-Give him three in the morning.  -I got it from here, Charlie.
我们会照顾好他的
He's in good hands.
-那 我退休了?  -没错
-So, I'm retired?  -Yeah.
-正如你提过的的那样  -我现在退休了
-Just like you said you would.  -I'm retired now.
为退休干杯 为退休干杯
To retirement. Let's drink to that.
退休...
To retirement...
还有 伙计们怎么样了?
and, uh, the crew?
是的 他们很好 好得很
Yeah, they're good. They're good.
-查理  -嘿 吉塞尔
-Charlie.  -Hey, Giselle.
抱歉打断您 格林先生
Sorry to interrupt, Mr. Greene.
去赛场的班车十分钟后到
The shuttle for the track will be here in ten minutes.
不知道为啥 他们都叫我格林先生
For whatever reason, they call me Mr. Greene down here.
嘿 你们俩 下次再来的时候
Hey, you two, when you're in the neighborhood,
请多留一会儿
stop over, please.
我们一块儿看看比赛啥的
We'll watch the game or something.
没问题
You can count on it.
我爱你 大个子
I love you, big guy.
我喜欢你的新车
I like your new wheels.
-这是什么?  -五万块
-What's this?  -50K.
萨尔给的
Courtesy of Sal,
处理拜加的那一单
for taking care of the Beggar situation.
我想这是你应得的
Figured you deserved it.
你可以去拿资格认证什么的
You can get certified and all.
认证 是啊
Certified. Right.
或者我们可以拿去买点家电
Or we could buy appliances.
我打赌意大利的房子里肯定没有家具
I bet those houses in Italy don't come furnished.
是吗?
You think so?
可以不用再犹豫了 查理
Pull the trigger, Charlie.
哦 我忘了告诉你
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
托斯卡纳的博物馆里
The museum in Tuscany?
正好有标本制作师的空缺职位
Has an open spot for a taxidermist.
世界还真小
Small world.
"托斯卡纳 意大利"
全剧终 谢谢观赏
中文翻译 豆瓣@小小砍头